Guide to the Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: Film Activities 1980s-1990s
  - Lincoln Center programs and exhibition notes; t.ms. of talk given by Starr during 1967-1968 school year. New York 1967-1989 1 Folder (Box 9, Folder 89)
    (Includes correspondence regarding "Fantasy in Film" public school project developed by Cecile Starr.)
  - Laser disc information: flyers, clippings, correspondence, photographs. [v.p.] 1988-19941 Folder (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence and clippings regarding non-film friends. [v.p.] New York 1980-1998 1 Folder (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Fire Island related clippings. New York 1979-1992 1 Folder (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Grierson, John. Clippings, correspondence, and Starr's personal account of meeting the film critic. Photocopy of Starr book review for Grierson on the Movies (1981) in "Sightlines, Fall 1981. [v.p.] 1955-1981 1 Folder (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Receipts, reviews, and correspondence regarding film related books purchased by Starr. [v.p.] 1966-1998 1 Folder (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Kaufman, Boris. Materials, correspondence, and manuscript of article written by Starr. Starr's printed review of Dziga Vertov: A Guide to References and Resources printed in "Sightlines" Spring 1981. [v.p.] 1980-1981 1 Folder (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Harvard Film Archives. Clippings, programs, and reviews regarding film retrospective Starr participated: "The Emergence of Abstract Film in America." Cambridge, MA 7-11 December 1995 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - Reiniger, Lotte. Personal correspondence, accounts by Starr, clippings, obituary regarding the film animator. [v.p.] 1981-1997 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 100)
    (Reference to Starr's organizing Reiniger retrospective at the American Film Festival in 1980.)
  - Stearns, Monteagle and Toni. To Cecile Starr (and Aram Boyajian). Article by Antonia Stearns in House Beautiful, December 1994. [v.p.] 1977-1995 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Wright, Basil. Information regarding British documentary filmmaker. Correspondence between Starr, Wright, and others. [v.p.] 1974-1985 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Correspondence and clippings regarding years spent in France. Includes Starr article reprint from the Saturday Review of Literature (1955). Personal accounts by Starr. [v.p.] 1962-1988 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 106)
- Series IX: Cassette Recordings
  - Cecile Starr's notes and list of cassettes catalogued in Box 10. (See entry for Box 10) [n.p.] 1977 1 Folder (Box 9, Folder 96)
    Written notes refer tape #7: Canemaker's Animation Group, November 1977 and tape #14: Maureen Selwood, November 1977.
  - Audio cassettes labeled by Cecile Starr: (Box 10)
    1) AFA-Wilder Green and Steve Aronson with Cecile Starr, April 1977.
    2) Alexeieff & Parker (Paris) with Starr, June 1980.
    3) Blair, Vachel with Starr, March 1997.
    4) Blair, Vachel with Starr, April 1997.
    5 and 6) Canby, Vincent with Starr, April 1981.
    7) Canemaker's- Animation Group, December 1977.
    8) Dockum Film, Starr narration [n.d.]
    9) Canadian Animators: Drouin and Bindon, November 1992.
    10) Griffin, George, 1977.
    11) Feferman, Linda [not in collection].
    12) Jarnow, Al with Starr, 1977.
    13) Malle, Louis with Starr, 1978.
    14) Selwood, Maureen - Animators, November 1977.
    15) Mazursky, Paul with Starr, 1978.
    16) Munro, Grant with Starr, November 1990.
    17) N.F.B. Animators: Patel and Hoedeman with Starr, November 1990.
    18) Petric, Vlada, December 1995.
    19) Reiniger with Starr and others, 1978.
    20) Richter on film with Starr, [n.d.]
    21) Rickey, Carrie with Starr, May 1981.
    22) Snelson, Ken with Starr, 1979.
    23) Starr, Cecile on Len Lye (Donnell), 1985.
    24) Starr, Cecile on the New School "Film Criticism"; February 1976.
    25) Thacher, Anita (Metropolitan Museum) [not in collection].
    26) Whitney, John phone conversation (Russett and Starr); October 1987.
    27) Spiral Anthology (special production) 1985.
    28) Wright, Basil with Starr; 1985.
    - Cassettes listed under "Miscellaneous": (Box 10)
      Cecile Starr re. Randall Jarrell, William Pritchard interview.
      Robert Graeff regarding Werner Graeff No. 1 and No. 2. Michael Pressman with Cecile Starr 1979.
      Archer Winsten with Cecile Starr, No. 1 and No. 2, 1981.
      Stewart Klein and Cecile Starr, 1981.
      Cecile Starr on N.H. radio talk re W.I.F.E.[not in collection].